

Yener Bas
Front End Developer
(information-electron
ics technician)

# **Yener Bas**Nievenheimerstr. 1 50739 Köln

0049/176 7672 55 63 yener.bas@outlook.de

Portfolio: <u>www.yener-bas.de</u> LinkedIn: <u>My LinkedIn Profil</u>

### **About Me**

I am a German-speaking Front End Web Developer with experience in creating web apps with JavaScript & Angular. You can find my responsive websites and business apps comprehensively in my public portfolio. I started my IT journey with an apprenticeship as an information electronics technician and I discovered my interest in coding at the age of 15 and started building simple websites with HTML & CSS. While working as an IT admin for a large hospital, I decided that I wanted to expand my coding skills and to focus on software development full time. After building a myriad of projects I am looking forward to building on my first experience and starting my career in IT in a junior developer position.

#### Main Stack:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript, Angular
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### Side Stack:

- Git, APIs (REST), Google Firebase

# Skills

- Building Applications with JavaScript & Angular: I built landing
  pages and several web apps as well as OOP-based Jump and Run
  Games. In various projects, we were working with Github
  collaboration and also coded live together.
- Deep understanding of IT & Software: Due to my background as an IT and electronics specialist, I do understand computer software and hardware very well.
- **High sense of responsibility:** I am used to taking responsibility and working diligently as I always did in my job as an information-electronics technician.

# **Professional Experience**

## Universitätsklinikum Köln (Robert Half GmbH) / IT-Administrator

MAR 2021 - NOV 2021, COLOGNE

- Responsibility for all printing devices.
- Detailed processing of Tickets remote or throughout the clinic on site.
- Internal Customer Service in German, English & Turkish.

#### Use Unique Gbr / IT-Administrator

APR 2019 - MAR 2021, COLOGNE

- Responsibility for all electronic devices in Software and Hardware..
- Configuration and management of network elements, planning and implementation of network expansion projects.
- Monitoring and analysis of network traffic and setting up network connections and access rights.

Office-/information-electronics technician / Several Employers (Malteser Hilfsdienst e.V., BT-Kopier GmbH, lang informationssysteme GmbH & Co.KG, Printcom GmbH)

MAR 2010 - APR 2019, COLOGNE, BONN, ESSEN, OBERHAUSEN, DÜSSELDORF

- Service technician throughout Europe with the highest Kyocera certification.
- Contact person for everything in the entire scope, especially for printers, copiers and multifunction devices as well as for most devices in an office and its network.
- I have Europe-wide experience in the areas of an in-house technician, rollout team, and service technician in the field in private and business areas.

#### **Education**

# **Developer Akademie / JavaScript & Angular Web Development**Training

APR 2022 - AUG 2022, MUNICH

Project based coding academy. Main Stack: JavaScript, Angular

Portfolio: www.yener-bas.de

Extensive Coding School, Learning Front-End Development, Coding, Agile Project Management and building several projects in teams and alone.

# Georg-Simon-Ohm Berufsschule / Fachoberschulreife mit

Qualifikation

AUG 2006 - JAN 2010, COLOGNE

Apprenticeship as an office-/information-electronics technician.

#### Languages

German: native
Türkish: native
English: good